

Alexandros Papakostopoulos

RAN INTEGRATION ENGINEER

<u>■ a.papakostopoulos@gmail.com</u>

Q Athens

+306936092273

Profile

Experienced and dedicated Telecom Systems Integration Engineer, being at the forefront of cutting edge technologies and playing a major role in 5G deployment at the Greek market. Self-motivated Software Developer with full stack project experience in production.

Employment History

RAN Integration Engineer, Victus Networks

March 2014 — Present

- Integration and configuration of new RAN elements (BSC/RNC/eNodeB/gNodeB) in RAN Sharing scenario
- RAN dimensioning and performance monitoring according to engineering KPIs
- · Liaising with RAN vendor for introduction of new SW/HW
- Interfacing with Core Network for E2E integration
- Budget / RFQ preparation for RAN integration needs
- Integration of new SW releases / features
- Integration of major new technologies such as 5G, 4G+, VoLTE, NB-loT, IP Sec

RAN Planning Engineer, Wind Hellas

November 2006 — March 2014

• Cell planning / optimization

RAN Planning Engineer, Q Telecommunications

December 2004 — November 2006

• Cell planning / optimization

Education

University of Bristol

September 2002 — September 2003

MSc in Economics, Finance & Management

National Technical University of Athens

September 1997 — June 2002

Electrical & Computer Engineering

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Huawei RAN SW/HW

5G Protocols and Procedures

Backend development for web applications (Python Django)	Large datasets automation - Python (pandas, numpy etc.)
Performance data analytics tools (Qlik Sense, MYCOM NIMS-Proptima)	Platfom as a Service (PaaS) expertise (Docker, Heroku)
Frontend Development (Javascript)	Database Management (Oracle, PostgreSQL)
Languages	
English	Italian